

Abhay Khosla

Third Year Software Engineering

PROFILE

Address

29 Nolanhurst Heights NW Calgary, Alberta T3R1S7

Phone Number

+1(403)-402-4100

Website

http://abhay2412.github.io/

Email Address

abhaykhoslao@gmail.com

Date Of Birth

24 March 2001

LinkedIn

abhaykhosla

GitHub

Abhay2412

AWARDS

Paul Robertson Scholarship

Shaw Communications

Scholarship

February 2020

Schulich Engineering

Diversity Champions

September 2019

Schulich School of Engineering

Students entering their first year of study at the Schulich School of Engineering, who are committed to promoting diversity and inclusivity in engineering.

CERTIFICATIONS

Data Structures & Algorithms

in Python

May 2021

Learning Azure DevOps

LinkedIn Learning

May 2021

Responsive Web Design

freeCodeCamp

December 2020

Google Analytics for

Beginners

December 2020

Google Analytics for Business

LANGUAGES

Hindi Native **Punjabi** Native

Urdu

Native

HOBBIES

Basketball

OBJECTIVE

Versatile, meticulous, and results-driven Software Engineering student offering 2+ years of experience with building small business scale applications and project management. Confident communicator who builds strong working relationships and can effectively collaborate with diverse stakeholders on a day-to-day basis. Seeking a Software Engineering Internship opportunity ranging from 12-16 months, given my belief that technological advancements is a necessity to support the growth of various industries.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Kobold Completions Inc.

Software Developer

(May 2021 - Present)

- Responsible for preparing, importing, and entering historical data into the new
- Kobold Digital Backbone.
 Working with existing data sets in Microsoft Excel (CSV) and converting them into a format to upload via Python and Numpy.
- Working closely with the **DevOps** team to ensure historical data integrity.

Hoodoo Foods Inc.

Web Developer

(December 2020 - March 2021)

- Tailor coding requirements for the website creation, including e-commerce capability and specialized scripts enforcing the security of the site.
- Perform user testing and tested websites prior to going live on the domain.
- Generate feedback for various stakeholders with the design phase under tight deadlines.
- Implement website and integrate solutions into business operations.

AASEE (Association for the Advancement of Science and Engineering Education)

(June 2020 - January 2021)

Frontend Web Developer Intern

- Developed **HTML/CSS/JavaScript** fundamentals and discussed web application designs and ideas through weekly meetings.
- Leading a team of **4 engineers** in developing the website and utilizing **GitHub/Git** for collaboration.
- Optimized for a quick, responsive, visually appealing website using **React-Bootstrap** to resolve cross-browser and cross-platform issues

EDUCATION

University of Calgary

Bachelors of Science Software Engineering

(September 2019 - April 2024)

3.7/4.0

- Relevant Coursework: Introduction to Programming (C/C++), Data Structures and Algorithms (Java), Object-Orientated Programming (Java), and Discrete Mathematics
- Clubs and Involvements: First-Year Scholar, Indian Students Association, Schulich Aerospace Organization, ESS Peer Mentorship Program, and Schulich Ignite

SKILLS

Java Intermediate

Web Development

Python

Intermediate

Intermediate Expert

PROJECTS

C/C++

Twitter Bot

https://github.com/Abhay2412/Twitter-Bot

- Built a **Python** automating script which can reply to a user when mentioned with Hello World, included the library of **Tweepy**
- Scripted an application on Python which can Retweet and Reply to a given number of tweets in particular search criteria.

Knockout Kings

https://github.com/Abhay2412/KnockoutKings

• Utilized various libraries, classes and functions to ensure modularity and readability of code for others.